Genadi Tsolov

Software Developer

Address Sofia, Bulgaria, 1700

Phone 087 900 4618

E-mail genadi.tsolov@gmail.com

Linkedin www.linkedin.com/in/genadi-tsolov

I'm a software developer with a passion for creating all kinds of web applications and games, as well as studying about new technologies and programming languages. My goal is to extend my knowledge as much as I can, gain experience solving interesting problems and to improve myself as a person. I'm always up for a challenge, so go ahead and offer me one!

Skills

- Languages: JavaScript, Java, C++, SQL, HTML, CSS
- Experience in backend/server-side development with Node.js (Express)
- Work experience with React, Typescript and Redux
- Experience with Web applications, REST APIs and GraphQL
- Excellent knowledge of OOP & SOLID, Data structures & algorithms
- Working with relational (MySQL and PostgreSQL) and non-relational (MongoDB) databases
- Understanding and Experience with Version Control System (Git)

Education

10-2019 - Current

Bachelor of Science: Computer and Software Engineering

Technical University of Sofia, Sofia

Relevant Coursework: Data structures & algorithms, Object-Oriented Programming,
Relational Database Design and Management, Computer Fundamentals

09-2014 - 06-2019

High School Diploma

Vocational School of Computer Technology and Systems, Pravets

• Certificate of professional qualification - third degree in the professions "System Programmer"

Work History

10-2021 - Current

Web Development Apprentice

Boom.dev, Sofia

- Learn latest cutting-edge technologies, libraries and good working practices
- Get hands-on experience by working on production ready projects
- You can see all of my projects on my github profile https://github.com/genadi53

07-2021 - 08-2021

Summer Internship

Digital and Software Solutions, Sofia

- Created a working website with React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- Built and maintained a working database with MySQL, complete with error handling and data validation.
- Represented companies at industry trade shows and had direct interaction with consumers.